Timothy Dimock Papers, 1809-1887
Connecticut Historical Society
Timothy Dimock Papers
1809-1887
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Dimock, Timothy
1.5 linear feet (1.5 boxes, 1 volume)
Biographical Sketch
Timothy Dimock was born on April 7th, 1800 in Coventry, Connecticut, to Daniel Dimmock (also spelled Dimmick) and Anna Wright. He had eight siblings. He graduated from Yale in 1823 and spent 45 years as a doctor in Coventry. He was a member of the Connecticut House of Representatives in 1838 and the Senate in 1846. During the 1850s and 1860s he served as surgeon for parts of Connecticut’s militia, empowered to grant medical waivers for exemption of duty. Timothy married Mary Ann Moody (born circa 1812) on June 29th, 1826. She did on August 16th, 1838 after giving birth to a daughter on July 31st who died soon after birth. Timothy remarried on May 8th, 1839 to Laura Farnum Booth (born circa 1816). Her father was the Reverend Chauncey Booth. The two had three children: Daniel (born circa 1835), Maria (born circa 1844) and Henry (born circa 1845). He corresponded with a niece, L. Dimock, and a nephew, D.D. Clark. Timothy may have been a justice of the peace or otherwise involved in court cases. He died on April 24th, 1874. Henry Farnum Dimock attended Yale in the late 1830s and later worked as a grocer. He died on April 10th, 1911, leaving $40,000 to the South Coventry Library Association to build the Booth and Dimock Memorial Library, named for his father and grandfather.
Scope and Content
The collection is made up primarily of correspondence and legal, financial and personal documents relating to Timothy Dimock. Family correspondence includes letters to Timothy from his nephew D.D. Clark, and from son Henry to his mother Laura Dimock. General correspondence to Timothy follows the family letters. Legal documents consist of agreements and indentures, insurance records, court documents, and summons. Among the financial records are receipts, accounts, tax records and an account book. Timothy settled his father Daniel’s estate, and those records are part of the collection. Timothy’s medical career is represented by medical prescriptions and lists of ingredients for various treatments. Henry Dimock is represented by a composition entitled “Brotherhood of Man” and by financial records, 1865, 1886-1887. A number of items cannot be attributed to any one person. These include several compositions and French lessons, a wallet with an inked inscription containing several small documents and some human hair, and a small notebook and an account book. Of note in the collection are a Dimock family genealogy and a newspaper pattern for a shirt.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Dimock, Timothy, 1800-1874.; Dimock, Daniel.; Dimock, Henry.; Dimock, Laura Farnum Booth.
Subjects
Dimmick family.; Dimock, Daniel.; Dimock, Henry.; Dimock, Laura Farnum Booth.; Physicians --Connecticut --Coventry.
Contents:
- Papers
  - Correspondence to the Dimock family, 1839-1869, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Timothy Dimock from nephew, 1840-1867 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Timothy Dimock to nephew, 1859-1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to Laura Dimock from son Henry, 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General correspondence to Timothy Dimock, 1827-1846 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General correspondence to Timothy Dimock, 1852-1874 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Military/State Militia Documents and Record Book, ca. 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tax documents, 1862-1870 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Insurance documents, 1858-1868 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agreements/indentures, 1815-1853 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Legal/court documents, 1850-1865, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sheriff summons, 1846-1853 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Estate of Daniel Dimock documents/records (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Medical prescriptions/ingredients (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Henry Dimock “Brotherhood of Man” composition (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Unattributed French lessons (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Unattributed compositions (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Papers removed from account book (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Henry Dimock financial documents/receipts, 1865, 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Undated financial documents/receipts (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Financial documents/receipts, 1809 ca. 1825-1835 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Financial documents/receipts, ca. 1845 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Financial documents/receipts, 1850-1855 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Financial documents/receipts, 1856-1859 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Financial documents/receipts, ca. 1865 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial documents/receipts, 1870-1874 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Unattributed wallet (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Unattributed notebook, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Unattributed account book, 1850s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - James S. Whitney notebook, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dimock family genealogy, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Assorted documents (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shirt Pattern, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Account book, 1864-1866 (Volume 1)